<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://maki3cat.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://maki3cat.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-07-13T19:08:08+00:00</updated><id>https://maki3cat.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Psychology, features of the Safe Attachment</title><link href="https://maki3cat.github.io/blog/2025/psychology-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Psychology, features of the Safe Attachment"/><published>2025-07-07T03:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-07T03:55:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maki3cat.github.io/blog/2025/psychology-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maki3cat.github.io/blog/2025/psychology-1/"><![CDATA[<p>We can target at people of the safe attachment in our efforts of healing. People of safe attachment is very integral and balanced with both emotional and rational capabilities. There is no too black and white OR extremes in their life. They are <strong>balanced</strong> in both personal development, and interpersonal relationships. So they act as mature and stable in terms of emotional regulation, community fit-in, intimate relationships, and self-evaluation.</p> <p>We explore the safe attachment type in two directions: the personal and the interpersonal features.</p> <p><img src="assets/img/blog/1_safe.jpg" alt="Safe attachment type diagram"/></p> <h3 id="personal">Personal</h3> <p><strong>(1) Good Evaluation</strong></p> <p>For the personal part, the safe type has very stable self-evalutation which means they have accurate self-judgement. They know their strengths and short-comings, and they understand themselves and accept as who they are. They are not easily impacted by others’ judgement. And they have very clear value systems, so they know the right direction to go for. That is, they know the priorities for sure in their life.</p> <p><strong>(2) Seeing the Reality</strong></p> <p>The safe type lives at the present; they can confront the complications and limitations of modern people’s life. It is a common thing for kids to use illusions to regulate emotions. But when we become adult, this kind of illusion will hinder us in our navigation of life. This kind of illusion can make things sur-really ideal or catastrophical, and react in a totally wrong direction. Many of real problems of adult of life are brought by illusions. Obsession, emotional cheating, etc can be due to illusions. But the safe healthy type is more down-to-earch and adheres to the reality instead of illusions, and can live at the present.</p> <p><strong>(3) Good Management of Personal Needs</strong></p> <p>The safe tyep understands their needs: emotional, physical, inter-personal. And they know how to find resources from themselves, community or the society to satisfy their needs. They don’t expect others to read their mind; they know and they express their needs to the correct person without feeling ashamed.</p> <p><strong>(4) Effective Emotional Regulation</strong> They observe their emotions; and instead of surpressing the emotions, instead of being violent, they know how to regulate their emotions in healthy ways and let the emotionals pass. They allow themselves to be weak and vulnerable, and they express this part to the right people that are safe type (their mental strength) and close to them (boundary). And they also understand what messages these emotions tell them.</p> <p>These people are actually emotional intelligent which doesn’t mean they know how to talk charmingly but means they understand and regulate their emotions effectively and relate to and accept others’ emotions as well. They allow vulnerability for themselves and for others and they provide container for all’s emotions.</p> <p>So people of the safe type are sincere and consistent. They don’t pretend; they don’t please. And they accept what they are.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="bib"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[translation from a video on Blibli]]></summary></entry></feed>